<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ava Kiai</title><link>https://avakiai.github.io/</link><description>Ava Kiai</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>avakiai@gmail.com (Ava Kiai)</managingEditor><webMaster>avakiai@gmail.com (Ava Kiai)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 16:06:04 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://avakiai.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[Essay] Hello DALL-E!: Thoughts on everyone's favorite image generator</title><link>https://avakiai.github.io/posts/dalle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 16:06:04 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://avakiai.github.io/posts/dalle/</guid><description>Here is an essay I wrote for my friend Jan&amp;rsquo;s Substack, talking about the importance and possible future impact of DALL-E and similar algorithms.
Jan is a super smart and freshly minted PhD who just started working at OpenAI, the company that produced DALL-E as well as groundbreaking natural language processing algorithm, GPT-3. He kindly gave me access to DALL-E for this piece.
I hope you enjoy reading it and would be glad to hear your feedback!</description></item><item><title>[Talk] Die schnatternde Menagerie: An Introduction to Animal Communiation</title><link>https://avakiai.github.io/posts/sptg_talk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 18:35:04 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://avakiai.github.io/posts/sptg_talk/</guid><description>Yesterday, I gave a talk in the Interdisciplinary Colloquium of the Main-Campus-Stipendiatenwerk, of which I&amp;rsquo;m a scholarship holder. It was a nice practice to give a full-length talk in German, and a nice opportunity to blend a scientific talk with some music.
In the talk, titled &amp;ldquo;Die schnatternde Menagerie: Eine ethologische und musikalische Einführung in die Tiersprache&amp;rdquo; (The Chattering Menagerie: An ethological and musical introduction to animal communication), I discussed the semantics, grammar, developement, and evolution of animal communication calls, using examples culled mainly from the bird, bat, and primate literature.</description></item><item><title>[Outreach] Skype a Scientist: Talking to 4th Grades about bats</title><link>https://avakiai.github.io/posts/sas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 13:12:04 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://avakiai.github.io/posts/sas/</guid><description>Back in November, I had a great experience talking to a couple classes of 4th graders about bats. As part of the online scientist-teacher matching program, #SkypeaScientist, I linked up with Mrs. Phaedra Taft at an elementary school in Connecticut.
We talked about bat ecology, their hearing and vocal abilities, and their natural history. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken to 4th graders and I was pleasantly surprised at their sophistication of their questions.</description></item><item><title>[Outreach] Bat Talk at Max Planck for Brain Research</title><link>https://avakiai.github.io/posts/bat_talk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 13:12:04 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://avakiai.github.io/posts/bat_talk/</guid><description>I was delighted to give a talk to PhD students and postdocs at the Max Planck for Brain Research&amp;rsquo;s Halloween Party last Friday.
Bats play a significant role in the folklore and mythology of many cultures. In the West, their image is almost synonymous with all that is dark, spooky, ominous, and unknown. There&amp;rsquo;s hardly any Halloween shop or party or setting that doesn&amp;rsquo;t in some way feature these furry flying friends.</description></item><item><title>New digs!</title><link>https://avakiai.github.io/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 17:22:04 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://avakiai.github.io/posts/welcome/</guid><description>In an effort to translate my existing workflows into a format that&amp;rsquo;s both resilient and open source, I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated to a new site!
News from ongoing projects and any future essays or general-purpose tutorials will show up here.
Essays on more politicized matters will remain over at my Substack.
Thanks for reading! More soon&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>